<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Damien C. Jacques</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Damien C. Jacques</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Smartpop - Dynamic Population Mapping</title>
      <link>/post/smartpop-dynamic-population-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/smartpop-dynamic-population-mapping/</guid>
      <description>This Notebook details the steps of the analysis of the Dynamic Population WP of the Smartpop project.
Data Exploration library(data.table) Mobile_Phone &amp;lt;- fread(&amp;quot;/home/ubuntu/Dropbox/Research/Projects/SMARTPOP/Data/MobilePhone/OBE_traffic_per_antenna_201405_201504.csv&amp;quot;) ## Read 0.0% of 40194140 rows Read 9.7% of 40194140 rows Read 18.7% of 40194140 rows Read 29.4% of 40194140 rows Read 40.5% of 40194140 rows Read 50.1% of 40194140 rows Read 61.0% of 40194140 rows Read 72.5% of 40194140 rows Read 82.8% of 40194140 rows Read 94.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting Reads</title>
      <link>/post/interesting-papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/interesting-papers/</guid>
      <description>The list below includes some interesting papers from the scientific literature and the internet (under construction). An up to date bibtex file of my scientific bibliography (created with Jabref) can be found here.
Table of Contents  History / Archaeology Network Society Privacy / Ethics  
History / Archaeology Laser Scans Reveal Maya &amp;ldquo;Megalopolis&amp;rdquo; Below Guatemalan Jungle Tom Clynes. National Geographic, 2018.
 Using a revolutionary technology known as LiDAR (short for “Light Detection And Ranging”), scholars digitally removed the tree canopy from aerial images of the now-unpopulated landscape, revealing the ruins of a sprawling pre-Columbian civilization that was far more complex and interconnected than most Maya specialists had supposed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Casting Data Visualisation</title>
      <link>/post/air-casting-data-visualisation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/air-casting-data-visualisation/</guid>
      <description>This R Notebook describes the steps to download the data from the Air Quality API, convert them to R data and make some basic figures.
First, we need to load two packages to deal with the API request (httr) and format (jsonlite). You can use install.package(c(&amp;quot;httr&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;jsonlite&amp;quot;)) to install the packages.
library(httr) library(jsonlite) First, we need to get the ID of all sessions of interest (here, located in Brussels and with the tag ‘kid’).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nighttime Lights Calibration</title>
      <link>/post/nighttime-lights-calibration/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/nighttime-lights-calibration/</guid>
      <description>Plot Nighttime Lights Time Series for Senegal First, we load the Version 4 DMSP-OLS Nighttime Lights Time Series (downloaded from here).
library(data.table) library(raster) ## Loading required package: sp ## ## Attaching package: &amp;#39;raster&amp;#39; ## The following object is masked from &amp;#39;package:data.table&amp;#39;: ## ## shift library(rgdal) ## rgdal: version: 1.2-16, (SVN revision 701) ## Geospatial Data Abstraction Library extensions to R successfully loaded ## Loaded GDAL runtime: GDAL 2.1.3, released 2017/20/01 ## Path to GDAL shared files: /usr/share/gdal/2.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>